SHUYING YU

Goleta, CA, USA | +1 (510) 918-8012 | syu.shuying@gmail.com | esswhy.github.io | linkedin.com/in/shuyingyu

Summary of Qualifications

Research: 8+ years in qualitative and quantitative analysis in human behavior and decision-making using statistics, hypothesis testing, exploratory data analysis, regression, visualizations, interpreting results, delivering presentations **Programming:** Advance in R; intermediate in Python; basic knowledge of Spark, SQL, Stan

Tools: Microsoft Office, Google Workspace/G Suite, LaTeX, Qualtrics, Git/GitHub, HTML/CSS, Tableau

Relevant Experiences

Data Science Intern, Carpe Data, CA

Jun 2022 - Sep 2022

- Created multilabel classification machine learning models to predict which social media platforms subjects will likely post relevant insurance claim information to as a filter to increase flag rates, save time and resources for product delivery engineering team, and encourage product growth at a scalable size
- Completed an end-to-end 10 week project including preprocessing, feature engineering, and model training using scikit-learn in Python/AWS which resulted in >98% recall and precision rates for filtering irrelevant domain sites
- Created and delivered professional reports for weekly standup, sprint, and manager meetings, as well as presentation of project results to C-suite stakeholders to share insights and plan future goals of model in preparation for production

Consumer Insights Graduate Intern, Jam City, CA

Jun 2021 - Aug 2021

- Collaborated internally and externally on 10 concurrent projects over 10 weeks by designing, programming, and analyzing surveys administered to thousands of consumers to interpret insights and improve consumer relationships
- Created and delivered professional reports and presentations for weekly key stakeholder meetings to share and understand insights, receive and implement feedback, and discuss subsequent ideas for research which included adding new in-game features and investigating details of consumer churn, satisfaction, frustrations, and interests

Graduate Student Researcher & Analyst, UCSB, CA

Sep 2018 – Present

- Collaborate internally and externally on 3 large scale projects formulating research questions, selecting and applying methods, designing and analyzing survey data, and statistical analysis on human behavioral patterns (e.g., A/B testing, ANOVA, regression); outcomes include sharing data and providing weekly reports on results to key stakeholders
- Maintain reproducible workflow using .Rmd, .ipynb reports and version controlled projects with GitHub
- Manage over 10+ trainees in data collection and coding, and oversee 5+ trainees with independent research projects by setting weekly meetings for project design and conception, statistical analyses in R, and communication of results
- Create and deliver 4 professional presentations at conferences and publish 3 peer-reviewed manuscripts related to human behavioral patterns and accessibility of science for women

Project Manager, UCSB, CA

Aug 2016 – Aug 2018

- Established own independent research project while running lab's larger study of recruiting 80+ subjects, budgeted finances worth \$800k+, moderating interviews, designing experiments, and creating and giving presentations
- Implemented user-centered design by partnering with experts to tailor experiments on improving user experience and testing for behaviors across 150+ subjects
- Evaluated project performance by communicating updates with stakeholders to ensure progress and satisfaction

Leadership

Diversity, Equity, & Inclusion Consultant & Organizer, UCSB, CA

Jun 2020 - Jun 2022

• Contribute to weekly meetings with stakeholders and create large scale policy changes with objectives and key results for implementation that highlight commitments to welcome and value diverse experiences

Beyond Academia Executive Organizer, UCSB, CA

Jun 2019 – Jun 2021

- Networked with stakeholders, communicated ideas across 15+ members, initiated new marketing strategies and sponsorships, and organized and lead meetings to build successful programs related to pursuing non-academic careers
- Planned event for 500+ registered attendees, managed 5-8 workshops and hosted 40+ industry professionals

Education

University of California, Santa Barbara (UCSB), CA

Ph.D. Candidate, Psychological and Brain Sciences

Jun 2023 (Expected) Jun 2022

M.A., Statistics and Applied Probability

University of California, San Diego (UCSD), CA

B.S., Cognitive Science, Honors w/ Highest Distinction

Jun 2016

B.S., Psychology, Honors w/ Distinction

Jun 2016